<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COMP6[84]45 Slides</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on COMP6[84]45 Slides</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en-au</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/jsonp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jsonp/</guid><description>JSONP Origin vs Site Origin https://www.example.com:80
origin = scheme + host + port
Site http://www.example.com:80 https://api.example.com:443
site = private_domain + public_suffix
scheme, subdomain and port SOP (Same Origin Policy) Blocks resource requests to/from an external site
&amp;ldquo;External&amp;rdquo; is based on SOP: only requests from the same origin are allowed to use the resources
more secure but how people bypassed it isn&amp;rsquo;t xd
Cross-Origin Resource Sharing Obviously sometimes you need to access resources from another origin (e.</description></item><item><title>01: intro</title><link>/week1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 5 past the hour! week01 COMP6443 Thanks @melon for the slides Good faith policy We expect a high standard of professionalism from you at all times while you are taking any of our courses. We expect all students to act in good faith at all times
TLDR: Don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk
sec.edu.au/good-faith-policy
Whoami Jesse Merhi (Like that plant + &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rdquo;) Product Security Grad @ Atlassian (Monday Next week) Been interning there for about one and half years.</description></item><item><title>02: identity</title><link>/week2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 5 past! Week02 COMP6443 Thanks @melon for the slides What happened this Week? Challenges This week is not like last - it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard. But don&amp;rsquo;t give up! All of the challenges from this week forward ARE REALLY VALUABLE Reports Reports are really cool! They tell you, How you found a vulnerability. How bad it is. How to fix it. You will be doing this TWICE.</description></item><item><title>03: iam 2</title><link>/week3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 5 past! Week03 COMP6443 Challenges The first weeks challenges were due! If you want extra hints I can give them now for those challenges ;) From next week (week 4), the challenges are more difficult! So if you are confused still about how this whole process works&amp;hellip; ASK ME. What&amp;rsquo;s coming up? weeks 4/5: server-side injection SQLi, SSI, XXE, SSRF, SSTI, file uploads weeks 7/8: client-side injection XSS, JSONP, Clickjacking, CSRF Due dates Topic02 challenges: THIS SUNDAY 11:59pm Midterm: Week05 Monday Report: Week05 Sunday 11:59pm Reports Does anyone NOT have a group?</description></item><item><title>04: sqli</title><link>/week4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 5 past Week04 COMP6443 Upcoming due dates? Next Week
Monday during the lecture slot: mid-sem (0%) sun 11:59pm report01 (20%) topic03 challenges SQL SQUILLY Structured Query Language
Basically how you can find stuff in a database. Some examples of &amp;ldquo;Flavours&amp;rdquo; (different implementations of SQL) include SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL Server Databases
Tables Defined through columns Contain records each record potentially containing a value for every cell. How do I use SQL?</description></item><item><title>05: serverside</title><link>/week5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week5/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 18:05 Week05 COMP6443 H18A House cleaning Midterm How&amp;rsquo;d you all find it (trivial enough?) Gonna do some of them challenges later
This week Local File Inclusion Server Side Request Forgery Server Side Template Injection Reverse Shells Local File Inclusion / Server Side Inclusion Is what it sounds like. Getting the server to include a file on a webpage Uses includes Demo (Pico CTF) &amp;ldquo;Forbidden Paths&amp;rdquo; (Local File Disclosure)</description></item><item><title>07: xss</title><link>/week7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week7/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 5 past Week07 COMP6443 H18A Cross Site Scripting (XSS)
House cleaning Due Dates Some of the XSS related challenges are out now. Some are broken&amp;hellip;. thanks @melon These are due Week08 Sunday @ 11:59pm Report groups The second report is coming soon (I think) Same groups! But with feedback ;) Marks/feedback will be out at some point (But I marked your reports if you want some feedback today shh&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>08: clientside</title><link>/week8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week8/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 18:05 Week08 COMP6443 H18A House cleaning Due Dates All of the topic04 challenges are out They&amp;rsquo;re due Sunday Week08. Reports (general feedback) Consider context when determining impact, not everything is critical. Keep technical stuff out of impact/remediation. It should mostly be in steps to reproduce. Mitigating CSRF JSONP What did people do before CORS was available?
JSON with Padding
You can&amp;rsquo;t load a resource from another domain (but you can load a script).</description></item><item><title>09: devsecops</title><link>/week9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week9/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 18:05 Week09 COMP6443 H18A My Experience How&amp;rsquo;d you find the course
What&amp;rsquo;d you like What&amp;rsquo;d you dislike What can be improved https://myexperience.unsw.edu.au
DevSecOps Waterfall &amp;#x1f30a; vs agile &amp;#x1f3c3; Systematic/design vulnerabilities are much harder to solve than simple coding/logic errors.
This is exacerbated in the waterfall approach, as you don&amp;rsquo;t really go back to the design phase.
Waterfall &amp;#x1f30a; exponentially more $$$ to fix bugs later into SDLC we want to shift security left &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#x1f4bb; vms vs containers &amp;#x1f433; CVEs</description></item><item><title>10: advanced stuff</title><link>/week10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week10/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 18:05 Week10 COMP6443 H18A Final exam Overview wednesday, 3rd May 3 hours (1pm - 4pm) worth 50% whats in it everything is assessable™ not just stuff from wargames submit a short writeup explaination there&amp;rsquo;s also a shortish devsecops question how2hack my biggest tip is try not to stress out + practice, practice, practice start with recon before you write payloads CI/CD keeping it secure github actions (ramble) pre-commit hooks .</description></item><item><title>extended08</title><link>/extended8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/extended8/</guid><description>Java deserialization slides are available https://waugh.zip/6443/extended08/
Bypassing CSP Self What is &amp;lsquo;self&amp;rsquo;? who am I?, why am I here? can things only be loaded from localhost? Let&amp;rsquo;s consult the experts &amp;ldquo;The self keyword in a Content-Security-Policy header directive, &amp;hellip; is an alias for the same origin.&amp;rdquo; from https://content-security-policy.com/self/
&amp;lt;base&amp;gt;d tag specifies the base URL and/or target for all relative URLs in a document.
Demo How to resolve this CSP again lmao there&amp;rsquo;s a base-uri directive in CSP, specifying which locations can be specified to be the base Other ways to bypass file uploads: what if you can upload a .</description></item></channel></rss>